

ABDULHAMID NASIRU

Born on 20th May 1991 No 13 Benin Street, Malali, Kaduna, Nigeria <u>iabdhamnasb@gmail.com</u> +2347036893579

Graduated with Second class upper in Chemical Engineering, Abdulhamid Nasiru's passion lies in developing his community and helping the environment in any way possible. He has worked with several charity organizations and served as a leader in several projects. Abdulhamid also free lances as a creative artist. His interests include Media, Brand development and management, Math, Literature, poetry, art, technology and a special interest in renewable energy.

EXPERIENCE

01/2015-11/2015	Vicks Nigeria Brand Intern at Procter & Gamble Nigeria -Worked as the Associate Brand Manager in charge of managing the Multi-functional team in Nigeria and the Local delivery coordinating the teams across Singapore, India & South Africa -Supervised production of advertisement copies (TV & radio) and local airing -Budget management for Vicks Nigeria -Trained in Business writing and analysis
12/2015-09/2016	Asst. Lecturer in Mechanical Engineering department (NYSC)
	Kebbi State University of science and Technology, Aliero
02/2017	Co-Founded The Kids Must Program.
	An initiative aimed reviving the reading culture in children. And
	finding creative ways of teaching and motivating children to pursue and Enhance their creativity.
01/2017- Present	Kaduna State Ambassador for the Jamuje Initiative.
03/2013-06/2013	Process Operator at Kaduna Refining and Petrochemical Company
00/2010 00/2010	(KRPC), Area One (Crude Distillation Unit)
07/2013-10/2013	Process designer at National Engineering and Technical Company
0., 2010 10, 2010	(NETCO), Lagos
12/2011- Present	Co-Supervisor/ Head of Capability/ Vice President of Ideal Aid
	<u>& Development Initiative</u>
	-Works with the charity organization that works on helping the

start

education, health of the under privileged in the society from the

-As the Vice President worked on developing a structure that we use to host summer schools and other activities yearly

01/2014- 12/2014 President of Nigerian Society of Chemical Engineers (Student Chapter)

03/2013- 08/2014 **Vice Chairman for New Mill**

<u>Vice Chairman for New Millennium Youth Forum</u> (now Society for Drug Abuse Control and Enlightment)

-Co-founded the organization by developing a structure that was used to identify and help drug abusers via lectures and therapy

-Served as the Vice President

ACHIEVEMENTS

- 1. First Intern to wok as Associate Brand manager at Procter & Gamble Nigeria. Successfully supervised production of advertisement for Vicks Nigeria as my first assignment. Managed the market promotions post price up and led the proposal for a new market strategy for the brand
- 2. With Ideal Aid and Development initiative, we successfully hosted summer schools at a local government school and provided scholarship to a student to a private school
- 3. As president of the Nigerian Society for Chemical Engineers organized the first student lecturer event targeted at improving student lecturer relationship

EDUCATION

2009-2014 Ahmadu Bello University, Zaria

B.Eng. Chemical Engineering

2003-2009 Essence International School, Kaduna

SKILLS

- 1. Process simulation using Aspen HYSYS
- 2. 3D design using Inventor Fusion
- 3. 2D design with AutoCAD
- 4. MATLAB
- 5. Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Word, Microsoft Power point

LANGUAGES SPOKEN

- 1. English
- 2. Arabic
- 3. Hausa

REFEREES

- 1. Barr. Bashir Abdullahi (+2348033557087, bashlaw1@yahoo.com)
- 2. Mrs. Boma Harrison (harrison.bo@pg.com)